Guide to the Rand School of Social Science Records TAM.007
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI: Publications, 1906-1955; 113546
  - Subseries VIF: Course Bulletins and Announcements, 1906-1955, 113567
    - Correspondence Courses: I. Introduction to Socialism II. Elements of Economics, 1933-1934; 113665 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:58
    - Mid-Winter Bulletin, Jan 1934-Mar 1934; 113664 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:59
    - Evening Classes and Lectures, 1934-1935; 113663 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:60
    - Correspondence Courses. I. Intro­duction to Socialism. II. Trade Unionism in Theory and Practice, 1934-1935; 113662 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:61
    - Mid-Winter Bulletin, Jan 1935; 113661 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:62
    - Spring Term 1935, Mar 20, 1935-Apr 25, 1935; 113660 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:63
    - Thirty Years, 1935-1936; 113659 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:64
    - The Rand School Expects You, 1935; 113658 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:65
    - Rand High School, 1935-1936; 113657 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:66
    - Mid-Winter Bulletin, Jan 1936; 113656 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:67
    - Fall Term, 1936-1937; 113655 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:68
    - Fall Term Lectures, 1936-1937; 113654 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:69
    - An Educational Program for Winter-Spring, 1937; 113653 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:70
    - Fall Term, 1937-1938; 113652 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:71
    - Announcing the Opening of The Newark School, 1937; 113651 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:72
    - Winter Term, 1938; 113650 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:73
    - Trade Union Institute, 1938; 113649 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:74
    - Alertness Courses, Jan 1938; 113648 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:75
    - Fall Term, 1938; 113647 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:76
    - Political Training Courses: Fall Term, 1938; 113646 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:77
    - Trade Union Training Course, 1938; 113645 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:78
    - Newark School Calendar, 1938-1939; 113644 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:79
    - Winter Term Bulletin, 1939; 113643 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:80
    - Alertness Course: Spring Term, 1939; 113642 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:81
    - Courses for Group Leaders, 1939; 113641 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:82
    - Political Training Course, Jan 1939; 113640 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:83
    - Courses for Social Workers: Spring Term, 1939; 113639 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:84
    - Training Courses for Trade Unionists: Winter Term, 1939; 113638 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:85
    - Fall Bulletin, 1939; 113637 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:86
    - Alertness Courses: Fall, 1939; 113636 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:87
    - Training Courses for Trade Unionists: Fall, 1939; 113635 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:88
    - Announcement of Courses: Winter Term, Jan 15, 1940-Apr 18, 1940; 113634 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:89
    - Alertness Courses: Spring Term, Feb 5, 1940; 113633 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:90
    - Training Courses for Leaders of Youth Groups, 1940; 113632 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:91
    - A Training Program for Social Case Workers in Public Assistance: Winter, 1940; 113631 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:92
    - Newark School Bulletin of Classes, 1940; 113630 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:93
    - Fall Term: Announcement of Classes, Sep 16, 1940-Dec 19, 1940; 113629 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:94
    - Alertness Courses: Fall Term, 1940; 113628 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:95
    - A Training Program for Social Case Workers in Public Assistance: Fall, 1940; 113627 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:96
    - Youth Education Institute, Sep 1940; 113626 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:97
    - Newark School Calendar: First Term, 1940-1941; 113625 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:98
    - Announcement of Courses: Spring Term, Jan 13, 1941-Apr 17, 1941; 113624 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:99
    - Alertness Courses: Spring Term, 1941; 113623 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:100
    - Fall Term Bulletin, 1941; 113622 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:101
    - CPA Examination Review Courses, 1941; 113621 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:102
    - Program: Fall Dinner, Newark School, 1941; 113620 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:103
    - Winter Term Bulletin, 1942; 113619 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:104
    - Fall Term Bulletin, 1942; 113618 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:105
    - What Every intelligent Worker Should Know, 1942; 113617 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:106
    - Fall Term Bulletin, 1943; 113616 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:107
    - Winter Term Prospectus, 1944; 113615 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:108
    - Trade Union Training Courses prospectus: Winter, 1944; 113614 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:109
    - Trade Union Training Courses Bulletin: Winter, Jan 1944; 113613 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:110
    - Bulletin G: Spring Term, 1944; 113612 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:111
    - General Bulletin: Fall Term, 1944; 113611 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:112
    - Institute for Russian Studies: Fall Term, 1944; 113610 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:113
    - General Bulletin: Spring Term, 1945; 113609 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:114
    - Trade Union Training Courses and Labor Seminar: Fall-Spring, 1945; 113608 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:115
    - General Bulletin: Fall Term, 1945; 113607 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:116
    - Trade Union Training Courses: Fall Term, 1945; 113606 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:117
    - General Bulletin: Spring Term, 1946; 113605 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:118
    - Bulletin: Fall, 1946; 113604 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:119
    - Bulletin: Spring Term, 1947; 113603 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:120
    - Trade Union Training Courses: Spring Term, 1947; 113602 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:121
    - Bulletin: Fall Term, 1947; 113601 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:122
    - Trade Union Training Courses: Fall Term, 1947; 113600 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:123
    - Schedule of Courses, Rand school of Northern New Jersey: Fall Term, 1947; 113599 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:124
    - General Bulletin: Spring Term, 1948; 113598 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:125
    - Trade Union Training Courses: Spring Term, Jan 21, 1948; 113597 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:126
    - Schedule of Courses, Rand school of Northern New Jersey: Spring Term, Jan 20, 1948; 113596 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:127
    - Bulletin: Fall, 1948; 113595 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:128
    - Schedule of Courses: Fall, 1948; 113594 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:129
    - Schedule of Courses, Rand school of Northern New Jersey: Fall, 1948-1949; 113593 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:130
    - General Bulletin: Spring Term, 1949; 113592 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:131
    - Schedule of Courses, Rand school of Northern New Jersey: Spring Term, 1949; 113591 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:132
    - General Bulletin: Fall, 1949; 113590 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:133
    - Bulletin: Rand school of Northern New Jersey: Fall Term, Sep 22, 1949; 113589 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:134
    - General Bulletin: Spring, 1950; 113588 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:135
    - Bulletin: Spring Term, 1950; 113587 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:136
    - General Bulletin. Fall, 1950; 113586 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:137
    - General Bulletin. Spring, 1951; 113585 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:138
    - General Bulletin. Fall Term, 1951; 113584 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:139
    - General Bulletin. Spring, 1952; 113583 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:140
    - General Bulletin. Fall, 1952; 113582 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:141
    - Schedule of Courses. Labor-Management Relations and Trade Union Leadership Training Program, 1952; 113581 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:142
    - General Bulletin. Spring, 1953; 113580 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:143
    - Schedule of Courses. Labor-Management Relations and Trade Union Leadership Training Program: Spring, 1953; 113579 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:144
    - General Catalog: Fall Term, 1953; 113578 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:145
    - Catalog B: Labor-Management Relations and Trade Union Leadership Training Program: Fall, 1953; 113577 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:146
    - General Catalog: Spring Term, 1954; 113576 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:147
    - Catalog B: Labor-Management Relations and Trade Union Leadership Training Program: Spring, 1954; 113575 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:148
    - Spring Term Extension, 1954; 113574 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:149
    - General Catalog: Fall Term, 1954; 113573 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:150
    - Schedule of Courses. Labor-Management Relations and Trade Union Leadership Training Program: Fall, 1954; 113572 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:151
    - General Catalog: Spring, 1955; 113571 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:152
    - Catalog B: Spring, 1955; 113570 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:153
    - Schedule of Courses: Fall, 1955; 113569 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:154
    - Catalog B: Fall, 1955; 113568 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 54: Frame XIII:F:6:155
  - Subseries VIG: Correspondence Course Lesson Books, 1913-1936, nd, 113555
    The seventh part of the publications series consists of 11 correspondence course lesson books. These lesson books, which contain individualized reading exercises and questions, relate to various courses in socialist history and thought, trade unionism, economics, and social history. Some of these books were written by such noted socialists as Scott Nearing, Algernon Lee, Anna A. Maley, Nathan Fine, and David P. Berenberg. The lesson books are arranged in alphabetical order according to the author's last name. A full bibliographical citation for each lesson book is located in the complete reel list for this collection.
    - Berenberg, David P. The Fundamentals of Socialism, 1919; 113566 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 55
    - Fine, Nathan. Trade Unionism in Theory and Practice, undated; 113565 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Henderson, Elinor. Introductory Studies of the Capitalist System. An outline Course for Socialist Groups, undated; 113564 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Kantorovitch, Haim. The Elements of Economics, undated; 113563 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Lee, Algernon. An Introduction to Scientific Socialism, undated; 113562 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Lee, Algernon. Social History and Economics, 1913, 1918; 113561 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Maley, Anna A. Elements of Socialism, 1914; 113560 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Nearing, Scott. The Human Element in Economics, 1919; 113559 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Ohsol, John G., et al. Social Problems and Socialist Policy, 1914; 113558 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Robinson, Jesse K. Civics Digest of Federal, State and City Governments, undated; 113557 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Shulman, Frederick. Basic Principles of Socialism in Outline Form with Suggested Readings, 1936; 113556 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Subseries VIH: Ephemera, 15 May 1911-3 February 1955, 1911-1955; 113549
    - Rand School Ephemera, 1911-1919; 113554 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Rand School Ephemera, 1920-1929; 113553 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Rand School Ephemera, 1930-1939; 113552 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Rand School Ephemera, 1940-1949; 113551 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Rand School Ephemera, 1950-1955; 113550 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Subseries VII: Press Releases, Sep 1926-Nov 1955, nd, 1926-1955; 113547
    The final two parts of the publications series contain ephemeral printed matter (XIII:F:8) and press releases (XIII:F:9). The ephemeral printed matter is arranged in chronological order and includes commemorative booklets, circular letters, programs, announcements, flyers, brochures, handbills, leaflets, and postcards. Some of the most interesting items in this part are the programs for the Rand School Ball of 1920, 1921, and 1922; ten leaflets relating to a series of political talks given by Scott Nearing before the Rand School's Current History class in 1924; a leaflet for Charles Beard's 1930-1931 symposium entitled, "American Civilization Today"; announcements for the Metropolitan opera and Broadway show benefits; and two booklets commemorating the 40th and 45th anniversaries of the Rand School. The press releases are also arranged in chronological order, with undated items placed at the end of the file. Most of the press releases contain general information about the Rand School as well as announcements of lectures and special events. There are also several speeches in this part which were given by Rand School faculty members and quest lecturers.
    - Press Releases, Sep 1926-Nov 1955; 113548 (Box 78, Folder 2)
- Series VII: Addendum, 1910-1955; 313165
  - Advertising: Correspondence and Documents, 1940s-1950s; 313202 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Advertising: Courses and Documents, 1932-1939, undated; 313203 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Advertisements, 1945-1955, undated; 313204 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - American Labor Party, Special Investigation Committee, 1938; 313166 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - American Labor Yearbook, 1910s-1920s; 313205 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - American Labor Yearbook, 1920s (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - American Socialist Society (Including Minutes and Rand School Reports), 1910s-1940s; 313207 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - American Socialist Society, By Laws, undated; 313210 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Announcements (Press, Publications, Typescripts), 1919-1944, undated; 313167 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Announcements (Press, Publications, Typescripts), 1944-1949; 313168 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Announcements (Press, Publications, Typescripts), 1950-1955; 313169 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Austria - Trade Unions, Socialist Party, undated; 313211 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies, undated; 313212 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors: Reports, Minutes, Correspondence, 1920s-1950s; 313213 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Bookstore, Library, 1940s-1950s, undated; 313215 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Forum, 1945, undated; 313216 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Cards, undated; 313219 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1930s-1940s; 313221 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Symposiums, 1939, undated; 313222 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Contacts and Other Lists, undated; 313223 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Co-operative Educational Institute of Brownsville, 1923; 313170 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1926; 313171 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1940s-1950s; 313236 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Courses, 1930s; 313237 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Afros, John, 1938-1939; 313172 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Afros, John, 1940s; 313238 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Mailly, Bertha H., 1917-1943; 313239 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Publicity Related, 1940s-1950s; 313240 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Course Description, undated; 313241 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Course Feedback, undated; 313242 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Course Handouts, 1930s, undated; 313243 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Course Information - Afros [teacher], 1938-1939; 313173 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Course Lists, 1920s-1940s; 313244 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, undated, 1910s; 313245 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1920s; 313246 (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1931; 313247 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1932; 313248 (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1933; 313249 (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1934; 313250 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1935; 313251 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1936; 313252 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1937; 313253 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1938; 313254 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1939; 313255 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1940; 313256 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1941; 313257 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1942; 313258 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1943; 313259 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1944; 313260 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1945; 313261 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1946; 313262 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1947; 313263 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1948; 313264 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1949; 313265 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1950; 313266 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1951; 313267 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1952; 313268 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1953; 313269 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1954; 313270 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Course Offerings, Bulletins, 1955; 313271 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Course Outlines, 1930s-1940s; 313272 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Course: Points of Conflict in Modern Education, 1938-1939; 313176 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Course Schedules, undated; 313273 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Course: Social Work, 1939; 313177 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Curriculums, 1935; 313174 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Curriculums for Future Classes, 1920s - 1930s; 313175 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Economics, undated, 1931; 313274 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Educational Council, undated, 1915-1920; 313275 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Event Announcements, 1940s; 313276 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Finances, 1929-1952; 313178 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Finances, Invoices, 1930s-1940s; 313277 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - First Assistants' License Examinations - N.Y.C. High Schools, undated; 313179 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten Notes, undated; 313180 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten Notes and Messages (Rand School Administration), undated; 313278 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten Notes and Messages (Rand School Administration), undated, 1915-1950; 313279 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Index to Labor Articles, 1936-1950; 313280 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Index to Labor Articles, Subscriptions, undated, 1927-1939; 313281 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Index to Labor Articles, Subscriptions, undated, 1927-1939; 313282 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Index to Labor Articles, Subscriptions, undated, 1927-1939; 313283 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Index to Labor Articles, Subscriptions, 1940-1956; 313284 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Index to Labor Articles, Subscriptions, 1940-1956; 313285 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Index to Labor Periodicals, 1927; 313286 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Industrial Relations, Questionnaires, undated, 1946; 313287 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Institution of Socialist Studies Bulletin, undated, 1951-1952; 313288 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Institution of Socialist Studies Bulletin, 1953-1955; 313289 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Intercollegiate Socialist Society, 1913, 1943, undated; 313290 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Job Opportunities, 1940, 1941; 313291 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Klein, Blossom - Personal Documents, 1949; 313292 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Labor History and Industrial Relations Typescripts, undated; 313293 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Labor Theater, undated; 313294 (Box 61A, Folder 1)
  - Latin-American Affairs, May 1952-Oct 1955; 313295 (Box 61A, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Announcements, 1935-1944, undated; 313296 (Box 61A, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Bureau, undated, 1938; 313297 (Box 61A, Folder 4)
  - Legal Documents (Agreements, Transcripts, Etc.), undated, 1919-1945; 313298 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Little Theater, undated; 313299 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Lusk Committee, 1919; 313181 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Mailing Lists, 1920s; 313182 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Mailing Lists, Etc., 1950s; 313183 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts, undated; 313184 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts: Labor and Socialist Topics, undated, 1919-1946; 313300 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Concert, 1932-1936; 313301 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Concert, 1949-1950; 313302 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Reports, Questionnaires, Notes, undated, 1930-1952; 313303 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Newark School of Social Sciences, undated, 1937-1947; 313304 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Other Organizations, undated, 1940-1946; 313305 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - People's House Bonds, 1927, 1928; 313306 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - People's House Cafeteria Records, undated, Apr 1918-Apr 1922; 313307 (Box 62A, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1939-1947; 313308 (Box 62A, Folder 2)
  - Professors, Lecturers: Related Material, undated, 1932-1951; 313309 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Publicity, undated; 313185 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Publicity, 1922; 313186 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, Jul 1924-Nov 1924; 313187 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Publicity, Dec 1924-Apr 1925; 313188 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Publicity, undated, 1934-1936; 313314 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Publicity, 1931-1940; 313189 (Box 63, Folder 8)